<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Norris Hung</title>
    <description>Norris Hung is a designer and front-end developer based in San Francisco. He strives to simplify and humanize by making products more usable and  content more understandable.
</description>
    <link>http://www.norrishung.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.norrishung.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 10:24:27 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 10:24:27 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Happens in Four Years</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot has happened since I built the last iteration of my portfolio in 2011. Looking back at it, I see a time capsule of web development four years ago. Web typography was still just taking off with Cufon and sIFR were the de facto methods of custom typefaces. Wordpress was your only option for a blogging platform. Pixels were still something you can discern on a screen and websites were built for a single dominant width.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to present day and the playing field has completely changed. @font-face has taken off and &lt;a href=&quot;https://typekit.com/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;font&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webtype.com/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.typography.com/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;services&lt;/a&gt; offer robust and legal means of beautiful web typography. The mobile market explosion has mean that &lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com/article/responsive-web-design&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;responsive web design&lt;/a&gt; is the only way to work these days. Retina screens are a thing and we now have to hack our way around &lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com/article/responsive-images-in-practice&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;responsive images&lt;/a&gt;. Static site generators have become a popular means of serving up performant websites. Transitions and animations have helped to make the web more fluid and interactive. And, of course, pre-processors like &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://lesscss.org/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;LESS&lt;/a&gt; exist (how did we ever work without them?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been keeping up with a lot of these changes at my previous job at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inkling.com/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Inkling&lt;/a&gt; and was delighted to finally have the time and opportunity to update my portfolio to modern web standards. I wanted to share some of my decisions here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;website-platform&quot;&gt;Website Platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last 4 iterations of my portfolio, I used Wordpress. It served me well over the years but I decided I finally needed to ditch it as it offered way more power and way less performance for what I needed in my personal site. I found that for my basic purposes, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; provided all the functionality I needed and it also allowed me to host my website on GitHub. I have found it super intuitive to use and way more performant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;responsive-images&quot;&gt;Responsive Images&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With more and more views coming in from mobile devices over cellular data, the size of images are a &lt;a href=&quot;http://timkadlec.com/2013/06/why-we-need-responsive-images/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;huge concern&lt;/a&gt; both in terms of data transfer speed and processing power of those devices. This is especially true when you also take into account retina screen optimized images. Luckily, there are responsive image solutions with &lt;code&gt;srcset&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;picture&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element and, while these are still far from widespread support, polyfills exist so that we can use them today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my current portfolio, I utilized the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scottjehl/picturefill&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;picturefill.js&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/robwierzbowski/jekyll-picture-tag&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Jekyll Picture Tag&lt;/a&gt; plugin. It was amazing how easy it was to set up and, as Jekyll was compiling my site, my jaw dropped at how much time I would have had to spend creating all the image size variations by hand. The most satisfying aspect was noticing how much it improved site loading speed across devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hosting&quot;&gt;Hosting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of going with custom hosting, I decided to host my website on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; this time around. I was already using it for version control and it made sense to keep it all in one place, especially since it supports Jekyll. The one trade off with Github Pages is that it doesn’t allow third party Jekyll plug-ins which meant that I couldn’t rely on GitHub’s server-side Jekyll compiler to generate my site. As a small inconvenience, I am now hosting my source website in one repo and rsyncing it to my compiled website in another. It’s a little frustrating but totally worth the responsive images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;styling&quot;&gt;Styling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do all of my work in Sass these days and I can’t imagine having to ever write vanilla CSS again. The use of partials, variables, and mixins have allowed me to keep my CSS DRY and well-structured. Of course it’s important to keep in mind what your compiled CSS looks like and to make sure you don’t go overboard with selector nesting. For this purpose, I use my former colleague Tom Genoni’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://cssdig.com/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;css-dig&lt;/a&gt; chrome extension to keep myself in check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is built responsively so that the website should be a pleasure to read no matter what device you are on. CSS animations and transitions help to make interactions more smooth and obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of browser prefixing and a flexible grid system, I opted in for &lt;a href=&quot;http://bourbon.io/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Bourbon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://neat.bourbon.io/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Neat&lt;/a&gt; from the guys at &lt;a href=&quot;https://thoughtbot.com/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Thoughtbot&lt;/a&gt;. It’s an elegant and lightweight library that does what I need and doesn’t come with the rest of the cruft. Bourbon also plays better with Jekyll’s built in compiler than Compass does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-typography&quot;&gt;Web Typography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been in love with the typefaces from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.typography.com/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Hoefler &amp;amp; Co&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve used their typefaces in a lot of my print work and work at Inkling and finally decided to bite the bullet to personally pay for their webfont service. The typefaces used are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.typography.com/fonts/mercury-text/overview/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Mercury&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.typography.com/fonts/whitney/overview/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Whitney&lt;/a&gt; - a pairing I’m absolutely obsessed with right now. My only complaint with this service is that you certainly have to sacrifice a bit of performance for beauty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phew. That’s it for now and I’m pretty proud of the technology stack that I’ve used to build this website. There’s no sign that the industry of web development is slowing down and I can’t wait to see what will change in the next four years. Personally, I’m hoping to see more of a convergence between web design and native app designs. I believe natively digital conceptual models like Material Design are here to stay and the capabilities of web design will need to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.norrishung.com/writing/2015/03/25/what-happens-in-four-years.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.norrishung.com/writing/2015/03/25/what-happens-in-four-years.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jazz Brewing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Jazz was born out of a frustration of the current available of brewing software out there. As with many niche markets, the leading software was developed by a passionate individual but lacked the technical or design expertise to build a product with a great experience. It serves many homebrewers well but we asked ourselves - what would a well crafted and modern brewing product look like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jazz is an ongoing project between Lere Williams, Greg Wahnon, and I.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“People don’t want drills. They want holes” is a great quote I once heard. Instead of focusing on the software, I first set out to understand what brewers were trying to do. I interviewed a couple of fellow homebrewers to seek and understand the different steps of brewing and the frustrations they had at each step. I found that brewing starts way before the actual brewing - it starts with getting inspiration and trying to figure out what ingredients were available to them and goes all the way to evaluation and taking notes on the beer after its finished. With an understanding of the landscape, we set up to brainstorm different ways in which technology could help with each stage of the process. We then worked to scope a feature set for an MVP. From there, I started working on wireframes and user flows. High fidelity mockups were created and used to guide the development of the software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently in the process of developing an MVP which we can then bring out users at homebrewer club meetings to test. Their feedback will continue to be incorporated into our thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 07:50:30 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.norrishung.com/interface/2015/03/18/project-jazz.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.norrishung.com/interface/2015/03/18/project-jazz.html</guid>
        
        <category>UX/UI Design</category>
        
        <category>Front-End Development</category>
        
        
        <category>interface</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mindshare</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Mindshare is a mobile/web app that helps you discover what your friends love reading online. It is a continually evolving project between Lere Williams and myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project was born out of the frustration that we spend more time sifting through junk than reading worthwhile articles and essays. Most current content sites generally rely on algorithms (Facebook Paper), community upvoting (Hacker News), or editorial curation (Bold Italic) in order to help their audience find articles they like reading. While these succeed to varying degrees, we believe there is an open space for a service dedicated to aggregating only articles that your friends have enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My role on the project includes UX/UI design and front-end code including styling, templating, and client javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mindshare is built with Meteor, CoffeeScript, and Sass. It also includes a Chrome extension that allows users to easily share articles from the browser. Webfonts provided by Hoefler &amp;amp; Co.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 07:50:30 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.norrishung.com/interface/2015/03/18/mindshare.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.norrishung.com/interface/2015/03/18/mindshare.html</guid>
        
        <category>UX/UI Design</category>
        
        <category>Front-End Development</category>
        
        
        <category>interface</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Feats of Strength Brewing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Feats of Strength Brewing is a beer-making collaboration between Lere Williams, Greg Wahnon, and I. After brewing together for two years, we decided our beer and audience were finally deserving of something that looked more professional. Instead of simply slapping on a pretty label, I pushed for a more considered approach to define a brand that reflected ourselves and the way we brewed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking inspiration from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cooper.com/journal/2012/5/elevating_the_brand_and_visual&quot;&gt;Cooper’s Experience Workshop&lt;/a&gt;, we started off by jotting down as many concepts and words as we could think of when we thought of brand values. With a wall full of these ideas, we took votes on the ones that resonated with us, ones that we strongly disagreed with, and ones worth discussing. From there, we were able to create thematic groupings that we wanted to embody and wanted to stay away from. We found that the wall of of rejected ideas were just as informative at shaping the brand as the wall of approved ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, I moved on choosing typography pairings, colors, and finally imagery and, from that, created three different design directions. We narrowed down to the direction we liked most and created physical prototypes of various layouts. The final choice was finalized and sent to printers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-result&quot;&gt;The Result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The values we came up with were “made to share”, “quintessentially modern but with a nod to tradition”, “restrained”, and “scientific precision”. Values to stay away from were “trendy”, “farm to table”, “sterile”, and “audacious”. Typefaces Brandon Text and Caslon were chosen to provide the contrast between modern and traditional. Brandon Text, being a geometic typface also spoke precision and science. A lighter color palette was choosen to make the design feel warm and approachable. The use of historical woodcut brewing illustrations in the background gives the label a textural complexity and a clear nod the tradition of brewing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 06:50:30 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.norrishung.com/identity/2015/02/22/feats-of-strength.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.norrishung.com/identity/2015/02/22/feats-of-strength.html</guid>
        
        <category>Visual Design</category>
        
        <category>Branding</category>
        
        
        <category>identity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Traverser</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At Inkling I built web tools in my spare time to solve problems. Working on dozens of book over the first year, I began to wonder whether I could do anything to make the process easier for other team members. What started off as hacking projects ended up becoming incredibly useful tools still used in the company today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Inkling, I built various tools to help content editors do their jobs more easily. Traverser was a tool that helped editors proof links in digital books. Users could quickly navigate between links using keyboard shortcuts. This turned days worth of work to hours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 06:50:30 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.norrishung.com/interface/2014/01/04/traverser.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.norrishung.com/interface/2014/01/04/traverser.html</guid>
        
        <category>UX/UI Design</category>
        
        <category>Front-End Development</category>
        
        
        <category>interface</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Poptip Viewer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At Inkling I built web tools in my spare time to solve problems. Working on dozens of book over the first year, I began to wonder whether I could do anything to make the process easier for other team members. What started off as hacking projects ended up becoming incredibly useful tools still used in the company today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, I was watching an editor proof content within glossary poptips. To do so, she scrolled through every page of the book tapping on each term to check if the definition matched. I watched her do this day in and day out and I thought there must be a better way. I spent the a couple of days prototyping a tool that visualized every poptip in the book next to the term that it was associated with. This transformed a task that took an entire day to something that took an hour. This feature was so useful that it was eventually incorporated into Habitat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 06:50:30 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.norrishung.com/interface/2014/01/02/poptip-viewer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.norrishung.com/interface/2014/01/02/poptip-viewer.html</guid>
        
        <category>UX/UI Design</category>
        
        <category>Front-End Development</category>
        
        
        <category>interface</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Frommer&#39;s Day by Day</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Frommer’s brand travel guides are among the most respected in the world. At Inkling, we were approached to create the digital versions of their Day By Day series guidebooks. Over the course of 8 months, we created 14 digital guidebooks that included interactive maps, local weather dashboards, slideshows, and detailed place of interest poptips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the technical lead on this project, I was responsible for defining and maintainable a scalable HTML/CSS framework for the entire series. I worked closely with the design lead to translate design mocks into responsive web layouts and stress-test them to make sure we both understood how the designs would respond across devices and text flow/image size edge cases. I was also resposible for building out a style guide in which our production team in India would use to build every page of the book and lead communciation with them when problems arose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since every book we built was essentially a complex website with dozens of page templates and commonly reused patterns, utilizing the power of SASS partials, variables, and mixins was crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 07:50:30 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.norrishung.com/content/2013/03/13/frommers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.norrishung.com/content/2013/03/13/frommers.html</guid>
        
        <category>HTML5</category>
        
        <category>CSS3</category>
        
        <category>Sass</category>
        
        <category>JavaScript</category>
        
        
        <category>content</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gilroy&#39;s Atlas of Anatomy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My role as a designer at Inkling was to translate a diverse range of complex print layouts to responsive web layouts that accurately captured the intent of the content. Working with media rich text allowed me to refine my typography skills in establishing type hierachies, balanced page templates, and flexible grid structures. Our continual goal was the push the envelope of what beautiful digital content could be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While most textbooks were straightforward to design, Gilroy’s Atlas of Anatomy presented unique challenges because this book was made entirely of images laid out on large format pages. Talking with the publisher, we realized that the ability to compare images and tables on the same print spread was crucial to the function of the atlas. As the design lead for this project, I focused on three main usability points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reduce the visual noise as much as possible to let the images speak for themselves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;allow for comparision of images at different levels&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;utilize the interactivity of digital media to help students gain comprehension of the material.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 07:50:30 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.norrishung.com/content/2012/08/15/gilroy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.norrishung.com/content/2012/08/15/gilroy.html</guid>
        
        <category>Visual Design</category>
        
        <category>HTML5</category>
        
        <category>CSS3</category>
        
        <category>Sass</category>
        
        
        <category>content</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Campbell&#39;s Biology</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As the technical lead on this project, I was responsible for defining and maintainable a scalable HTML/CSS framework for the entire series. I worked closely with the design lead to translate design mocks into responsive web layouts and stress-test them to make sure we both understood how the designs would respond across devices and text flow/image size edge cases. I was also resposible for building out a style guide in which our production team in India would use to build every page of the book and lead communciation with them when problems arose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 07:50:30 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.norrishung.com/content/2012/04/02/campbell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.norrishung.com/content/2012/04/02/campbell.html</guid>
        
        <category>HTML5</category>
        
        <category>CSS3</category>
        
        
        <category>content</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stages of Nitrogen Loss in Food Production</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Many times, I find myself thinking about what the numbers actually are when reading about environmental claims. I’ve decided to start making information graphics illustrating answers to these questions. This first graphic follows the trail of industrially produced nitrogen and the inefficiencies in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began with a static infographic below but I realized that it was not correctly illustrating the scope of the problem. As a result, I recreated the piece as an interactive graphic. As I wanted to lean more towards a graphic than an piece of interactive media, I tried to keep the complexity down and for it to neatly return back to its original form at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 07:50:30 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.norrishung.com/data/2010/08/03/nitrogen-loss.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.norrishung.com/data/2010/08/03/nitrogen-loss.html</guid>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
        <category>Flash</category>
        
        
        <category>data</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
